[Music]
they leave europe for america they leave
egypt for the promised land
they leave and that's where the exit
exodus what i call exodology
is tied to the savior and the society
and the messiah
and that's the story we need today
because the only proper response
to the pagan lynch mobbing that is about
to explode right now it's not just that
it's the story we need today
it is the story it's like um
it's true that we need it today but we
always need that story on some level
like it's kind of a universal thing
right
you know what it is it is the actual
historical events but you could also
just
it's just it's just that it just it's
always been the case
that the one guy who's not going to
you know not going to join the mob
um becomes the the savior and then leads
the people to a new
reality or a new promise and then
that's why the south comes from the
outside world walking in
he comes from the future walking in so
for example today
the future this is of course what
cerakus is now working on
we're working on digital we're working
on a global
we're working on all the things that are
needed today
for the proper exodus to save the
fucking planet so we're working on
equatopianism we're working on
cosmopolitanism
we're also working on reinstituting
religion properly with the border
absolutes it starts working again
so it's religion about maturity and
about adultification
all the things religion should be
concerned with so we're basically
looking through all of the history of
religions to find out a pattern here
that actually makes sense today
so we cannot go for the pop version this
time but go for the proper full-on
religion
that requires maturity deep studies and
and and
and devotion but only minority will
accept it we are not prepared for
anything else we're not going to go for
the pop numbers like
islam and christianity and american
culture does all the time
we're going to go for a slow graduate
growth and few people
who understand what's going on and we're
going to present them with the idea that
there's an exodus that is available
it's not literally from one territory to
the next it's in exodus
out of physical into the digital realm
to then revisit physical
from the digital realm and that's
exactly what we're looking at
facebook and twitter um uh
um oh they're dead already they're all
now they're all now under class
phenomena just like
if you look at twitter they there are a
few superstars that's what everybody
else follows it looks exactly like
television it's act like mass media
it looks exactly like any damn broadway
show you could ever have
i'm not interested in that's following
in the number i'm anymore i'm not
interested in quantity anymore
the first thing you view religion
properly is you forget about quantity go
for equality
this is exactly what you do if you're a
moses you're going to find your
people and it's a monotheistic cult in
egypt it doesn't want to be part of
polytheistic egypt any longer we want to
create a monotheistic society
to make to see if that works this is the
beginning of nationalism
and what zoroaster did in persia was
that he inspired people to to
to go for an idea of imperialism now
this is stretching the human imagination
way beyond the clan of the tribe they
were born to be comfortable with
but today sacred chambers are pagan
they're only clans and at best strikes
the lynch mobs are not in the clans that
are the best tribes it's called
intersectionality
it's pretending that the different echo
chambers have a shared goal
they don't they only have a shared
abject and it's the white heterosexual
man
who they are allowed to attack as much
as like because it's the only thing that
creates a sense
of togetherness between the echo
chambers because as soon as the white
tetrasexual man
removes himself from the scene or fights
back the war is over
that's the problem with objection so
they have nothing else in common
they are nothing but tribal in the the
lowest possible sense the subcultural
phenomena
there's no culture to intersectionality
it's nothing but subcultural
so anybody who comes alongside and
provides a greater narrative
to an elite mind you but you start with
to an elite
and talks about a new paradigm a new
condition of life which is
of course the marriage between man and
machine and you start to welcome that
you start to answer the question what is
the machine going to ask us
once the machine is here that is
preparation for the messiah
and it's always the people who instead
of finding an anarchic and stay within
the pagan lynch moments always the
people who said no
let's let's let's skip that all together
let's prepare
for the savior to come yeah for me that
question today is very jewish
yeah because the savior hasn't already
come like in christianity it is very
strong the jewish people
is zoroaster you're always waiting for
the muslim the messiah is in the future
it's not that the person says at the end
of the old empire when the old empire is
falling apart
the end of the thousand-year rush this
is originally persian ideal hitler stole
at the end of the thousand-year rush
this ocean
can come and this awesome can come if
you prepare for the session to come
and the solution is to split fellas to
come to lead us into the promised land
meaning the social says
i'm going to lead you into the new
paradigm so you don't have to be part of
the downfall of the old one
who does this today anybody who leaves
academia
anybody who leaves politics anybody
leaves mass media
and moves online it creates youtube
channels and do the podcast the webcasts
out there and start exploring new ideas
and
find new friends around the world and
bridges languages and
gets out of the echo chambers and goes
into the mode of antagonists
where can i be challenged where it can
be antagonic
where can i find somebody who i can grow
with who challenges me
that those are the kids i look for today
because they are going to be deleted
they're going to be ready for the
session when the session comes
and if i'd be the machine and i
certainly would be there is some kind of
super intelligence to be confronted with
humanity
i would go for all the humans who
prepared for me and i regard for the
humans who had some kind of quality that
i don't have
because the next split phallus we need
is to split between machine and man
the logos of the machine are the pathos
of the men of mankind
that's where i'm looking next to prepare
people for the savior to come the logos
of the machine and the pathos the paths
of mankind
[Music]
to create a new mythos the new narrative
of their combined marriage
okay now if you're not even in that game
if you're not interested then
so be it but you're going to be left
behind you're going to be stuck in old
egypt with the locusts and the
starvations and everything
because you're not going to be part of
the people who leave and do the exodus
this time to the promised land
this is why i talk about exodus i talk
about a study of exodus
throughout history who leaves
when the chance is given well the
working-class people in europe are left
for america
in the 19th century did pretty well
except now they've gone corrupt
they ignored their own history it took
them only 150 years to ignore their own
history
and now when you got the lynch moves the
pagan lynch running all over america
ignoring even the christianity
of the forefathers they're lost
they haven't learned a thing and that's
because after 1945 they were all
fostered to become to become
infantile teenagers with youth worship
instead of wisdom worship that's where
america went
wrong america went wrong because it got
so big at it after won the second reward
that he believed in james steen and
marilyn monroe the new gods
you'd have no pantheon of all these gods
who killed themselves
the warnings are everywhere and
underneath that the lynch mobs come out
of colleges in academia and america
today
and they're just furious and they're
full of themselves and they're
narcissistic
and all they want to go do is to go
after some abject out there to kill kill
kill kill
with internal domination it's incredibly
pagan yeah
and but also and then then there's some
figures that come like martin luther
king or whatever who are
who are not like that no but they was
like there's a few of them they're sort
of the
like as you would say they were there
they only take martin luther king's
black skin
color to stealing into their lying
mythology at the moment
they don't listen to martin luther king
at all none of these kids ever read karl
marx none of these kids ever read
friday's nietzsche
they don't understand things like hayden
heidegger at all but they certainly
haven't even read martin luther king
have they even read barack obama i doubt
it
because not even him not even obama was
a celebrated victimhood
not even he did this complete turnaround
that happened after obama left how the
lynch mouse were let loose
and intersectionality go over american
college discourse it's
it's it's terrible
the iron of it all is when they demand
that we should what defund the police we
should respond defund the academic left
start right there stop giving them money
cassess their fuel money and attention
like they still get detention so be it
they get their attention within the
record chambers but
if we give them any more tax money from
now on if the americans or the europeans
keep giving tax money
to the academic left that has created
this mystery to begin with
that would be a terrible mistake yeah
well it's it's it's
i was talking to zach stein and it's
it's it's all
it's education right it's like education
and and
and uh and religion have to become
one thing again on some level i think
it's ethics to it
and ethics as well sure yeah i don't
think exactly but people aren't getting
it
aren't getting a meaning education
they're getting uh
they're not getting a aesthetic
education they're getting an ideological
education so
if you just say you're going to educate
them you still haven't attacked the
basic problem
why in what way would you educate them
out of the it's not a lack of
information well their hassle education
it's a lack of damn morality it's a lot
to have teacherly authority on some
level and you have to you have to know
that you're a kid and you know nothing
first yeah is it any damn
culture i ever studied any nomidology
any metric will go forward to the young
man smack him in the face
and say without me you're nothing
if i leave you to walk under the
wilderness being 20 years old for
yourself you're dead
after 400 meters a tiger jumps up and
bites you kills you because you know
nothing about nature and if you know
nothing about nature how can you know
anything about culture
you're not natured you're not cultured
you're not educated but if you're just
gonna provide more information or
flatter the kids to know that they're
great kids and they can stay
kids forever but just being educated
more and more
i don't think these guys in america
understand the severity of their crisis
yet
because they still haven't gone deep
down into esther prior to the united
states of america to understand where
paganism comes from
and how paganism and christianity are
different and how removing christianity
from the agenda
means automatically replacing it with
paganism again because there is no
atheism
it never was so you're you're you're
being very pro-christian
today it's uh alexander you're you're i
mean
yeah you're saying america needs good
old
christianity again no no
there's no way back it just needs to
understand that if you skip christianity
you get paganism and it's even worse
you can't go back you can't be ironic
christian because christians were
seriously christian
you got to understand what is the point
to the whole christian story
and these days it cannot be separated
from the other stories
you cannot go back and start with the
jews or start with the greeks
you got to go deeper freud started
digging into the egyptians
i followed freud after gibson's into the
persians
then i discovered you need to go to the
indians and the chinese
you need to study all the narratives of
the world today
you cannot go and claim any sort of
grand narrative
by being a westerner only talking to
westerners because westerners have asian
indian and persian neighbors we're
changed forever
there's no way back to christianity as a
world religion christianity must be
understood as adventology
and evantology is one of the two
religions that's possible
the other one is nomidology no we're all
becoming
india because hinduism is fundamentally
normatology
and brahmanism is fundamentally
eventology
you can also go into buddhism that's
exactly how the separation of the
buddhists within different schools
what the tibetans and the persians have
like the indians is that they have a
separation of schools
there's one religion for the priests
that's like ultimate truth finding
whatever that is no matter how the truth
is they can handle it
there's the military order which is
always the heroic and the hero kills the
dragon and therefore
he sets the humanity free and therefore
he gets to fuck and then he becomes the
hero
and then you got the matriarchal
religion which is religion that the
child
and the woman is at the center of the
universe and everything returns
to the same because the mother will give
child
the birth to her daughter and the
daughter of the mimic the mother they
give birth to the next daughter
and that chain of the key
sets the tone for the nominology i will
never ever argue with nominology
it's the ultimate truth even the
universe operates that way
but i would say that's a possibility for
an evantology based on that
and young men today will go kill
themselves and lose themselves to
bipolarity and depression
like beyonce like i say looks i wish you
success
we all see depression pandemics you all
see by polar dependence among young men
coming
because they're stuck now with no
fallows
we need new chieftains we need priests
that we need a new narrative for the new
chieftains of the new priest we need new
visions
and and these missions are always
catalyzed
through engineers who build skyscrapers
and who merchants who trade and then
build temples
is the skyscraper the temple that we
brought back in again what are we going
to be how are we going to build the
future well i've got projects for you
if if you think of human engineering
combined with artificial intelligence we
could finally solve the problem of
nuclear fusion power
wow if we did okay we need ar for that
we'll know that
but if we did that would be the first
thing i asked the ai to do
the next thing i asked i had to do is to
translate every language to every other
language
people can finally start communicating
one another on the other hand they would
also have crypto which means you can
lock
in every action that we do forever so we
ethically are
forced to behave in ethical manner from
day one
it's cruel but it's the only thing that
will work that's what crypto's so damn
brilliant
and with that you can also work on a
cause of politicism because if you can
understand other cultures and get
curious about them
they're no longer enemies and we can
live in a shared world now these
impossible dreams are possible if you
bring aia into the system
and if this is what we ask the machine
to do
it sounds like a christian i don't know
[Music]
eventological that's the word not
christian so it's all about what we ask
the machine to do
yeah the machine itself is the event to
us like christ was on the cross
like sorraster's understanding of
ventology was to the zoroastrians
like the exodus out of egypt was the
jews
yeah this is the islam too it's most
this muhammad between mecca and
medina but it's always at an occasion
that's right it's an occasion at a
certain point in time the change sister
forever
that sets the agenda for a certain
eventological religion
so i'm defending eventology
[Music]
we should go back to whiter versus
heidegger that's i'm still
flabbergasted about i got more
understanding of heidegger but maybe
thomas can
do the whitehead interpretation here i
got into uh heidegger i tried to read
him a bit but
i'm much more at home in whitehead i
have no idea why everybody
um by heidegger is so much more popular
than them
than uh whitehead it's quite puzzling
i i can i can understand why it's more
popular because he's an individualist
and he's like the last
he's an existentialist and he he speaks
to people directly on their own
spiritual journeys
but i i am a huge white head fan i i
think white it is
after hegel then there's whitehead these
are the giants
uh um i would prefer if i do see more
popular but
it's precisely by reading heidegger
rereading highly geared today like young
chauhan does the same thing
he's really hiding through hegel and i
try to read him through whitehead and
that's how i came up with this idea of
the of not only the sources but phallus
and relationalism being foundational
but heidegger's hatred towards dasman
and towards the inauthentic person who
hides within the mass
and that's kind of what's beautiful
about heidegger actually yeah
yeah so heidegger takes the coward
which stands in the center of the crowd
it's completely inauthentic
has done nothing but mimicked and it's a
big coward and still
picks up a rock to throw
to throw out the object now wait a
second
you have not had a spine in all your
life
and you're picking up a rock to throw
out an innocent object
who probably personifies what you hate
about yourself
but by killing him you can disguise the
fact you hate this about yourself so you
can thrive on it still and
stay within the mode of resentment this
is where heidegger follows nietzsche
and i find that interesting because that
inauthenticity hydrogen speaks up
has to be that has to be added to gerard
because iran works with the social
dynamics and heidegger works with the
inner world
of this cowardly creature i think even
just the mass
gerard said that heidegger was the way
to go next he sort of said i i've i've
written up to this point and then
there's something next beyonce
is the bridge between the two so if you
read connecting you read you know the
the the um and there's total disregard
for
habeasian disregard for for crowds and
the power of crowds like
and if you read that to understand the
lynch bumps today
i mean heidegger becomes an asset but
you read connect and then sees your art
as an even more complex kinetic that's
the way i reach your art
he takes canada's thinking even further
understands dynamics even deeper
by going also even deeper into history
and i mean we read canada a lot we we've
used him a lot said the christian eye
with certain uc rap these days
uh and i'm kind of surprised that i can
use heidegger with whitehead also to
understand
how power then breaks through in the
system how the tyrant steps forward
how the tyrant has nothing to do with
the messiah figure and i'm
so relieved in seeing them as total
opposites
in every way possible
what do you think of uh thomas what do
you think of alexander's idea about the
machine
and uh being the event of our time
what do you think of that all that yeah
if you're a machine intelligence expert
right you're
yes i do uh i do stuff with ai and
uh probabilistic programming stuff like
that um
yeah i mean it's it's a bit like i mean
if you if you just if you look at like
for example
uh uh the christian religion right
there's some kind of
huge event that happened right so this
this this whole
story of christ and then the revelation
of the victimization
mechanism and that had an enormous
effect on on the on the course of
history
um tom holland wrote a really great book
about that uh very recent called
dominion
i highly recommend it because he kind of
kind of says what an enormous
kind of makes clear what an enormous
event it was and what you had before
and after that event so the the world
before christ was very
i mean it was very cruel and concerned
for victims was completely
absent right so that was an enormous
event and and right now
we are we are again having an event like
that right there's something that
emerges
and that is going to take us to a
completely new direction
uh in for the rest of the history of
humanity and uh
yeah i think it's it's it it fits in
this eventology idea right so that that
that you uh you have these events that
create uh
create um yeah that have huge
consequences
i don't know about uh
you know the messiah thinking around ai
and things like that i mean i'm kind of
like very pragmatic about it for the
time being
it is the relationship again it's a
relationship with the mana machine that
is messianic not the machine itself
again relationships can we do with that
image i mean
okay so we can say that but okay okay
okay
we all know we all know that nuclear
fusion power is an incredibly famously
difficult engineering project to
undertake
we know if you would succeed with it
calculations show that if
it occurs within the next 60 to 80 years
we will solve all the major problems for
example
connected to climate change today you
could actually even
water the deserts and the old you know
the old dream of cosmopotamia like
you could drown everything in the river
and everything can grow everywhere
that that fantasy can become true so we
could solve all the problems current
problems of climate change if we have
access to
cheap abundant electricity forever which
is the nuclear fission power promises
but the complexity of the engineering
not only is incredibly expensive to
build
and it's going to take a long time to do
to request god to do that
hey no ai could speed up that process
easily with decades at least
and any engineer would agree to that so
that's a perfect sample way i could do
because it's all about saving time and
that's what saviors do
they save us time they they take us into
the future
now and jump
the jump into the future is to jump into
the promised land
so that the problems we're stuck with
here are gone and we can survive
that's fundamental too so man versus
machine but but about
about how we construct the abject
there's one word we're missing here and
that's martyr
how do you pronounce that in american
english be murder murder yeah
uh we we actually what was that
self-sacrifice or murder george
george floyd was turning to murder right
yeah
he's not a scapegoat he's a martyr so
and that's interesting because the
murders
is what lynch mobs thrive on because
because lynchpots pretend that they're
leaderless
again they pretend the an object does
not exist because there's nobody there
it's just a shared idea that they thrive
on right
so that's the anarchic because the an
object is there
they all that happens is that they then
become completely dependent on the
martyrs
because they cannot have a sign of a
leader when they walk forward say this
is how later we follow him
or her no instead they take the mothers
and put them on the plaque cards and
then they got to demonstrate and have
the martyrs everywhere
and they want to have george floyd
statues and george floyd birthdays and
george floyd mostly go into the calendar
and all the heroes have to be removed to
be replaced by the martyr
and that's why the martyr is something
we should explore further
er before we take our next study because
and the difference between the murder
and maybe the saint right
no yeah exactly because the martyr will
be tied to the anoject ejected the
tyrant
in that sense whereas the saint
would be tied to the savior and the
lesser gods
[Music]
because the saints most of the christian
saints are supposed to be martyrs of
some are many of them are
martyrs of some kind well these are
problematic with words you always
discover they probably
but the martyrs of christianity martus
prior to becoming saints
then they become saints and when they're
saints they're acknowledged as lesser
gods you can pray to them
and the beauty of catholicism is that
they it has the lesser gods
therefore just like zoroastrianism it
has a polytheistic
bottoms up religion called iconology at
the bottom which is for
what which is not martyrdom yeah
i think so you got the saints lesser
gods then you've got the superior gods
but they're only for the priests and
possibly for the military
and the superior gods are vague and
abstract and they're really pointing
towards the one god
so top monotheism elitist
only for the league and of course the
monotheism should be
locked up behind the bard absolute and
people should gladly have enjoyed all
the lesser gods in their iconology
that is what india did that's the ideal
religion if you want a religion to
survive for 5 000 years and that's
another 5 000 years coming
that would be hinduism and that's
exactly what hinduism operates
if so asterism did the same thing except
that prioritized monophthous elite
sweden so people could aspire
it's precisely because they created the
mentality so people could aspire to a
better world which india never did
this is the shift between iran and india
but they
so rasta was wise enough to allow the
folk religion to prosper
that's exactly why the soros invented
universal human rights because you could
have any religion like
astonishing on the iconological level
you expect women and children to worship
astrology no problem right
but you expect boys to worship
conspiracies no problem you can have
that
as long as the leadership the chieftain
the priests
operate within the realm of the one god
and the one god is the phallus that
split
only dictators want to unify the
followers and that's when they fail
but martyrs yeah that's next
that's next i think that the history of
heresies is also very interesting yeah
so i mean you can kind of see like like
we have like 2000 years of christianity
right and so
so there's all these discussions about
uh you know people think of these are
very arcane issues and
they're very you know not related to any
real world issues but
but it's not correct actually i mean you
can you can see that these heresies even
though they look kind of silly why are
they you know
why are they arguing about this this
arcane aspect of religion but
but it had real effects in real life
right so so you could actually see like
there's a there's
something growing here that will go in a
direction that we don't want
so there are all these there are all
these for example there was this
i think pelagius so this was a guy who
uh so at some point the christians were
were forced to hand in their bibles by
some roman emperor right
and then and then there was this sect
that said like and every christian who
did that
is going to hell so those people are not
true christians
and then there was another another uh
group of christians who said no we
should forgive them
and it's so and it's the last uh group
that won
so and you have a lot of these
discussions going on in the history of
christianity it's very interesting to
see
how uh how the the modern day
christianity is basically the result of
this of this 2000 year conversation
right
and a lot of things that that we think
are oh this is absolutely essential to
christianity no this is something that
was
made up by some guy in the 11th century
and that then spread so the first
thousand years this was totally not on
the table
so this is very interesting so actually
looking at your religion as
a process which it is right that that
tells you a lot i think that that also
keeps it sane right you can kind of see
that there's no
there's no absolute truth here that's a
very good point you know this is
actually something that constantly
constantly evolves and that's why i'm
i am very i mean i christianity i find
it super interesting to
study it and also do certain christian
practices and read the bible and stuff
like that
i mean you you learn a lot from it uh
and and it's also
basically i think the trick is to get
but many of the great christians like
meister eckert were
were considered uh you know heretics too
i mean also oh yeah
hey i love meister eckhart like i could
read him for
days it's just so beautiful but but he
was a heretic and so was uh
most of the great medieval saints were
sort of heretics weren't they or
many of the great any free thinker was
always a heretic heretic is just having
a different opinion than popular opinion
it's it's like
okay if popular opinion is the anobject
which it is
then anybody poses the analytic the ana
and objectives by
the vulgar is the heritage so heresy is
just another name for plurality
yeah but they had sensors and they would
go through all of oh of course
eckerd's so do we today underline
things that you know okay what the fuck
is the platforming the platforming is
going after the heretics it's the same
fucking shit all over again
it's the people who are totally
intolerant and won't allow the different
opinion
they expose their weakness by going
after you so anybody
kills heretics is exposed exposing a
weakness
now there are instances in history where
maybe killing a few of them like killing
a nazi or something is at least
excusable or killing an islamic state
warrior is excusable
uh the sorastian thought so in the
assassin of the empire because they
found the
gnostics to be problematic when
gnosticism
moved out of being something pillar
since practice in the woods that became
mass movements
they were terrified of the master kites
they were terrified of the mannequins
and i insist that the master kite and
the manichaean
heritage is what we still have problems
with today in ideology
i am a strict modest but i'm a modest
like spinoza who believes in
infinite amount of attributes now
and i'm a i'm i'm practicing
transcendent emergencies now as
transcendental emergencies fundamental
philosophy
which you can build paradigm theories
and things like that too that i do my
philosophy
now that that is the whole richness of
what i try to do with circus but
it's gonna make sense and it's all tied
together right it's
it's a worldview but of course you want
to be challenged but
at least now we appreciate the heretics
except
the social justice warriors don't but at
least in a society there's an open
society practice
free speech it becomes more intelligent
and innovative because of it
that's why i speak of antagony as a
great we need heresy on some level too
antagonise appreciating and loving the
heretic for challenging you
that's what the word antagony means and
to be antagonic it's not antagonistic
antagonic means i'm out there looking to
expand our worldview can somebody please
challenge me
can i find a heretic please you know
it's
looking for the heretics act to look for
the heretics is what antagon means
and it's a better word than democracy
because it's an ethical commitment
to the different it's very darn living
us
it's not democracies to democracies just
a power play it's probably over and done
with
we need something much more deeper
substantial
to appreciate the different opinion to
to depreciate the richness of variety
which is required for innovation
the chinese communist party cannot be
innovative it can't
it can only mimic and make a mimic
it cannot move into the turn trick it's
stuck in the sutra which it then
you know with machinic acceptitude tries
to accomplish
but it will always fall apart i think
you're gonna have a major natural
disaster soon in china that has to blame
the chinese communist party i don't i
don't know how long cnp will last but
i don't think it will last that long to
be to be honest about it i think it's
unattainable
to rule china today the way he does it's
impossible
so antagonia you're describing that as a
political system i i'm trying to
understand what you said antagony is an
ethical principle
it's a rastine principle but it's a
greek word antagonia
antagony means i am looking for those
who
challenge me please can i have them
right it's an encouragement of the
heritage of the heretic
rather than trying to deal with the
heretic when it pops up
mm-hmm yeah invite them in for tea
yeah yeah we do this in sweden
his talk show has gone huge he and i sat
down after all the brouhaha
concerning me in black lives matter he
and i just sat down had a two-hour
conversation
and we have over 500 000 views on
youtube
suites only ten million people that
means one out of twenty tweets
at least has watched the entire two hour
episode when i explained to navid
direct questions on why i acted the way
i did during the black lives matter
and people get it they get it i mean
that's the power of youtube right now
that's antagony i'm said i'm
you're listening to me okay here i
present my case yeah
like soccer is without and and i'm
gladly i gladly
participate in discussions and of course
after i've done that
we have these islamic guys in sweden who
called me saying
you're great man and you like heroes and
you don't like victims but we don't
either
we don't want to be part of this victim
of worship thing so why don't we do a
podcast in september and i said yeah
sure i'm gonna do that i'll
gladly sit down with these guys all
kinds of ethnic backgrounds and skin
colors or whatever
and talk to them and i would love to
listen to their stories because i'm an
antagonic i love to hear the story of
the other this is derrida's ethics
and i think that that's what should we
practice today
that's some kind of fantastic love of
the strength that's the kind of
infinite love of the stranger no just a
natural curiosity that your neighbor is
different from you
wow tell me what's that like that's
enough
that's real this infinite love of
strangers thing that you know critically
tried to do after derrick does just
no i don't believe in those kind of
ethical imperatives that's exactly where
the bourgeois hypocrisy starts you know
it becomes virtue signaling sounds great
and
it sounds you know unfathomable and any
poor person would say that's impossible
to begin with anything that rich people
try to do the poor people can't do is to
begin with bullshit
ethical principles can be led by by
anybody
actually ethics is about dealing with
poverty more than anything else
it's not it's not ethics is not about
how to look posh when you're wealthy
no ethic is all about give away your
fucking resources to somebody who can
get education from them
and it could grow and prosper because of
it that's ethics and then it's about how
to deal with poverty poverty
awesome great speech
[Laughter]
thanks for the page i'm inspired let's
go
we're getting there let's go let's go
getting a mob
and just kidding
well the good news is that we have all
these stinkers that we can
we can read and study and understand
what's going on right whitehead
heidegger
gerard yeah and and it's so accessible
right i mean i
i mean uh you know i had alexander over
a
a couple of days ago and we were
discussing whitehead and all kinds of
stuff
and so it's it's it's this is alexander
all right janice genius wonderful guy
so and it's amazing how many people or
that the people are actually studying
these these texts and trying to
to understand the world based on this on
these concepts and these these
systems of thought and so we have a lot
of there's a lot of material to
understand what's going on
and uh and also have discussions like
these right they're not so much
they're kind of mental discussions right
we're trying to understand why are
yeah it's unaffiliated from any
institution
and it's independent and yeah because i
mean
self-organizing yeah all of these
activists right i mean there's often
some good causes right i mean uh being
against racism and sexism all that stuff
i mean we can be against that
but but it's also very interesting to
see well what kind of what kind of
dynamics
are are are being developed what kind of
what kind of groups are being
formed what's happening and like this
bigger picture right and then you you
quickly see that you that the
the the funny thing is that these this
hype these hyper modern times
and these these all this ai and these
computers and these networks
they basically bring back ancient
humanity
ancient patterns of behavior that that
were on the way out
and that are suddenly exploding and we
people don't know what to do with them
because
they don't have any religion to guide
them through it anymore so
they basically go back to very very
ancient patterns
and they do it on on 21st century
technology which is kind of a bit of a
scary
situation yeah and it because the
technology itself
creates the sense of now now now now and
that's precise we need to step back and
say wait this is only something
technology is doing to me and it's doing
to everybody else okay then it's
stupidity
it's mass stupidity that's exactly what
i'm talking about if you want to go into
the future going to the past
what's the first thing you do when you
realize that now is overhyped
yeah meaning any little change that
happens in the news is overhyped
constantly over-hyped over represent
represented so you tear down a statue
somebody built an empire 300 years ago
to replace it with somebody who just
happened to be a guy somebody talked
about in the gossip yesterday
as if that would be the equivalent
statue that that that that lack of
historicity is enormous at the moment
yeah my my what we're talking about
because we're submerged in the now right
where we're like
like there's a constant attack of the
now right oh yeah
so we need to get out of the now right
yeah and get in and now the worst
is exactly what's called feminine
hysteria it's not that
women want to be there they are there
they are intermediate
that's a mindfulness and all these
things are female as the women say
i got to feel it in and i got to see if
i got a lost or not about it and then
i'll decide if i do it but if i do it
i'm committed that's what women do
brilliantly
that's okay but if women do that and men
try to mimic that
rather than go into deep studies of
history and then look way
into the future for visions then what
the fuck are men for
that's what the priest and the chieftain
that's what the master and the hood are
about it's about
gaining the ground to then go into the
future and look forward
this is what ironically here again
compare religions the
dao in taoism yeah well the zen arrow
goes both directions right yeah and the
asha in zoroastrianism is of course the
way in christianity too
christ says i am truth i am way
and i'm life the truth
the way and the life are connected okay
they exist together in christianity too
so they are one of the same things i
would say there are two truths we're
talking about here
again priest and chieftain different
this goes for the truth as a fact
that's what we call logos factual truth
but the other truth is transcendental
truth which is truth as an
act which my students go after him about
all the time
this is the concept we discussed in
synthesism it's truth as an action which
points towards the future
and of course when i act with truth as a
fact
for example when i go to the court of
law which is a very priestly thing
when i look at the theological
philosophical matter when i look into
scientific matter
i look all into the past i look all for
the facts because facts are all about
the past
this is about truth finding facts
meaning finding fact from the past
meaning getting history correct why does
this mineral exist today
how does it operate how did it come
about what can we do with it
all those things are truth as a fact and
that is the priestly truth
but the transcendental truth that the
king or the
uh chieftain personifies is truth as an
act
and that is i don't have perfect
knowledge about everything
but at least i know where i'm going and
i need i'm going to the right place and
i've got the direction set
and i therefore make the best possible
strategy i could make with the resources
i have access to
to then make the impossible possible
this is why christianity speaks about
the truth
and the way and life and this
in so astronomism is repeated as asha
and asha where asha is just truth as
things suffer also literally means
how things will work but ah is how
things work
with the direction added that's an
awesome
act yeah that's why it's a state of mind
whereas
it's an ethical imperative so also is
that i want to personify
truth with the direction which is i i am
based in
truth ingrained in truth to go towards
truth
and you realize now the cult of the now
that we live at the moment
has no capacity for truth at all it only
has capacity one thing
my feelings that's why it's a crowd
obsessed what it feels
as if what it felt was truth that is the
ultimate
dangerous pagan lynch mob that ignores
truth completely and that's what i mean
with ignoring the famous
[Music]
so i think speaking makes sense towards
the future it makes
a lot of sense right
[Music]
true to the event yeah the truth of the
event is only what that actually happens
at the event but it's not something you
can take any information from or have
any guidance towards
[Music]
i like this truth as a fact and truth as
an act i think that's
that's that's very good way to think
yeah it's the difference between
intelligence and transcendence
gathering intelligence what's that true
the fact that it sounds a bit like uh
nirman akaya and sambogakaya
is i might get this wrong
um uh there's like one is
the they're called the three bodies of
the buddha and and so so one is
one is the the the appearance of the
buddha like the the buddha
and the other is is the subtle you know
uh non
it's it's the subtle aspect it's like
pure thought and then and then there's
the third which is the
non-dual which is um beyond the causal
on some level but um i i always i'm not
sure the connection
you're making thomas well i was thinking
about you know my car is just brutal
fact right of objective fact and then
someone gakaya's potential
and the narmakayas process oh okay there
you go okay that's right
wait wait wait more white heady and then
the mystical
languages i stopped reading the
the buddhist texts when i noticed that
whitehead was talking about the same
thing but
in a lot more well accessible way to me
and also very evolved you know very
systematic and including signs and stuff
like that so but there's actually a guy
who wrote the book about
the the connection between whitehead and
uh and
buddhism uh an australian guy is a very
interesting book
that's interesting do you remember the
title yeah i have it here it's
um it's a guy called peter paul
something i have it here somewhere
because
red airling is challenging me of course
they were working on a model for
pre-process so pre-relation meaning also
pre-physics
uh and and whitey was concerned with
this and you can't ignore it because
that would be the dharmakaya then if
it's not potential must exist before
actuality exists but
for us at least afraid elegant i'm
working on is the potential
is pre-process and pre-relation suddenly
relation occurs and the way i'm looking
at it is like in the membrane theory so
you've got
say fields of potential that no
connection one another whatsoever
but when they collide things happen
that's relation
and relation and kick starts processing
we're kind of going away from the white
hadian agenda right because then you
you kind of don't put relations as
as fundamental but you i think i know
why did
whiter dealt with relations was
fundamental to the world as we know it
so the world he discussed from plato
forward was some was a word where he put
relations at the center
therefore he's heraclitus responding to
plato in the way he works
but it's uh there is
states of there are states of potential
that
we call antique but not actual
now it gets really weird here right it
gets real domestic a lot of that but
david bowm dealt with this why to deal
with us and it's inescapable
you can't really do an emergence vector
theory
on to remove the primacy of physics or
remove the primacy of consciousness in
either end
so you see the reductionism of reverse
reductions you want to get rid of both
by making all emergence vectors neutral
to one another so each emergence vector
is discussed on its own merits it then
turns out the physics doesn't have a
need to be prior to chemistry biology
you can even discuss an emergency sector
prior to physics called subphysics
i work with hypertime and i work with
hyperspace in that sense
if for example the big bounce occurred
and space time then is created after the
big bounce
there's obviously something prior to
space
time we cannot think of it any other way
we need the hyper time axis to do that
it has to happen in some kind of
hyperspace to occur now
we can leave aside what hyperspace and
hypertime is for now that's a much later
question to solve if ever it could be
solved
but we have to pathetically state that
that to me means there are fields of
potentials
that don't have to respect space time as
we know it
and these fields of potential can then
collide
and when they collide we get existence
as we know it and that's how relations
kick in
and that's why anything meaningful to us
that we discuss
is process any meaningful task that we
discuss is relations
but it doesn't have to start with the
lashes or start the process
because we're going to remove the whole
idea at the start
is important the start is not the event
if you create a radical emergence vector
theory
because then it becomes more important
this is this is getting very close to
to science right i mean you you'll have
to get a physicist on the team i'm
afraid and then
read these there's there's a book where
they basically explain how uh
how whitehead's uh metaphysics fits
perfectly on on quantum mechanics
yeah so um so i mean that's that's a
very ambitious program something like
that um
or quantum organics as we call it it's
it it doesn't
listen as long as it doesn't challenge
anything
that physics speaks about today rather
it embraces a lot of ideas or physics
moving and makes them even more possible
and likely
which is a good sign uh it doesn't
that's the whole point this is
try or to or outside of or external too
and it's speculation and that's what
philosophers are allowed to do
and if they're good at it they have some
crazy while the distant physicists 50
years later come along and said hey
this is something i could try it could
make sense here locally
for example edward witton's membrane
theory if superstring theory is not that
interesting to put it in the
put it away somewhere and see if we ever
need it in the future maybe we can look
at it again
because we got stuck with it but
membrane theory is interesting as an
idea of universes
existing to begin with and i could then
think of membrane theory
the other way around like it's only when
the universe that we're interested in
the member of theater could be
interesting when we are
approaching the problem that for an
actuality to occur there has to be
something potential prior to it
which is an unavoidable question in
philosophy
and if you're gonna not gonna have the
constant effect out of a miracle out of
nothing the universally occurred i think
lauren's cross is fundamentally
wrong and sloppy and cheap and i think
no
we're getting towards something where
the big balance is probably going to be
the winning solution today and it's
going to change
physics radically when it happens and by
preparing the subphysics that actually
embraces that idea
with a really weird concept of
hypertonic
almost close to something worse circular
than linear
interestingly enough see where that goes
how far becomes stretched thinking-wise
brady and elon and i obviously are great
with sort of challenging other ways we'd
love to involve in those conversations
thomas
but we're really stretching each other
because
because uh boom and whitehead they are
they're actually
quite different right yeah but they they
they're they're asking the right
questions in a way towards
the natural sciences as friends of
natural sciences willing to extend their
scope
at least philosophically speaking i
think that the
bomb is basically a hindu and white is a
buddhist
exactly yes yes you can divide the world
into the hindus and buddhists right
that's the it's like the big division
right
the hindu after all sort of lovey-dovey
and the buddhists are like
well to you guys too guys okay so the
origin of eventology is of course to try
to get off the wheel of the eternal
recurrence of the same to begin with so
buddha's first attempt there is just can
i just get off
uh whereas our asterisk that says why
get off
why not use it why not create an event
well that's trunk
as well i mean that's yeah in tantra you
get that's right
it's not it's not getting off the wheel
it's a very nice
that's what i'm saying you can't even
speak or certain speakers or asterisks
and buddhism separate religions in that
sense they're different schools are
thought in one and each
and the ultimate extreme is of course to
take the most follicle religious rasters
and put it opposed to jainism and peter
here
he's really interested around here he's
really just in jainism at the moment
yes he's proud his father is sort of
fatherly rebellion against me i guess to
dig into giants and see what he can find
but it's interesting he's a character
that actually would make a really good
giant this month to be honest about it
it fits his personality perfectly
and and walk around naked
well if yeah if the big bounce turns out
to be true the giants and wins the war
of the religious
we have to go back and study it properly
because obviously we have
amounts of time and eons of universes
and hypertimes and whatever
that we have to deal with once we're
there and it's looking increasingly
likely we're going to end up with that
story
so we'll see we'll see where that
narrative is going to take us
it's not surprising to women anyway
because to women the eternal recurrence
are the same it's
it's just the way things are it's just
men that can't live with that idea
it's it's torture to think that
everything will return to the same
always without exception that's a
groundhog day is a masculine film that
women don't understand
that's sexist alexander you're going to
no
testosterone just driving you forward it
was nature's ultimate question it was
just like the eternal recurrence of the
same is the greatest study ever had and
i hate it
so he knew that and of course the lust
is the guy who breaks out of that and
understands it as
reversed buddhism which is what
delusionism is it's just like
the occasion of of the of the the
reoccurrence of the same has a slight
abbreviation this is a
slight difference that difference is the
difference of its difference in
repetition book
that difference in itself enables the
sun to imagine a world different from
his father's
but it's a phallic fantasy that's why
eventology starts with phallic it starts
with men
women don't want to improve the world
you just want to maintain it
that's it save it
fine that's why they're
environmentalists and that's when men
dream about becoming a ketokians
and together echotopianism
environmentalism just majestic
zoroastrians and buddhism
they're complementary antagonists
complementary antagonists yeah like that
yeah but one thing that is kind of
interesting is that so in india they
seem to be very good at having
these different religions uh living next
to each other
and people people seem to be very very
flexible so in europe of course we've
had
uh less success with that i mean you
know like
uh we had these these wars between
protestants and catholics
that went on for a long time and uh so
it's a it would
also be interesting to look into why why
is this is this uh
why is there this religious pluralism in
india with relatively
well the persian empire had it for 1400
years too before islam came along so
and china has practiced for most of its
history
it is because you separate simply you
separate religion
from state because you separate priests
from
king but then king and priests are both
part of the religion
so there's an overarching religion and
beneath that you can have iconology
i don't say politicism it's iconology
the worship of the lesser gods
but because we don't have iconology it's
in protestant europe a protestant north
america we invented celebrity worship
which requests terrible iconology
celebrities take tons of drugs and die
when they're young what the fuck
they're not good role models but those
are the girls yeah
god
but that's what we do people cannot live
without the lesser gods they they go
crazy so they will invent lesser gothic
sacrifice celebrity culture is just bad
religion it's
it's it's just again we're not atheistic
at all we just replaced christianity
with with this sort of pagan religion
full of idol worship and the idols we
worship our civil liberties and of
course the celebrities are even tired of
themselves
they walk off television they walk off
celebrity status they want to be zen
monks or whatever just leave
because nobody wants to be celebrity any
longer nobody wants a politician any
longer
nobody wants to be in the limelight any
longer why would you
why would you put yourself through such
horrors as being a celebrity
well you're the only one who would know
alexander
i left you left yeah
i was there and i was an alien i was
dressed in a fucking chicken costume the
last
season of sweden's got talent eerily you
know what the fuck am i doing this is so
weird i must stay
but now i'm over it sorry it's just it's
just it's totally over
i'm so relieved out of it and i love the
online world because you can go into
smaller audience
you can go into people who really are
interested in what you do that's a much
more natural way of communicating to
people
than just sending mass television with
crappy commercials
sending ice cream in huge packages to
fat kids it's just like
terrible right now i much prefer the
online world where you sort of
specialize and people just go away go
somewhere else if they don't find
interesting
i i find that democratization of media
incredible
and it's much more similar to having
monasteries where you can go and study
so you immerse yourself in
this is what i really want to study and
this is the teacher that you want to
have and
if i can have a teacher i'm going to
immerse myself and stay there for years
to study rather just
surf around across everything and say
the same stupid things that everybody
else does because
it's precisely the surfing and the
quoting of the skin quotes from the
same celebrities that creates the
current lynch mob culture
it's it's only togetherness on the
surface there's nothing deep to it
there's nothing profound to it at all
it's easy to join and it's strictly
emotional and demands nothing of you
except you must stay with the group
yeah this
celebrities even the good ones kind of
they they
fade away and they become specters and
ghosts of
yeah jordan peterson i'm surprised that
didn't happen to you
alexander you're just you're still here
with your high octane uh
but uh but no no but really i knew all
along i was a guest in that world
yeah i was there to possibly subverse it
and study it to then leave
because i knew when i started doing pop
culture the pop culture was going to be
incredibly important
the internet came along and knew yeah
it's going to be important for the first
30 years
after that we will cut it will count for
nothing the rock star is dead and over
and nobody's missing the rock star
why who needs rock stars and because
musicians today make a beautiful
scene imagine on instagram
sonic wallpaper is what music should
have been all along and now it's finally
a sonic wallpaper like brian enos
oh you're a brian you know guy yeah yeah
because that's what it should have been
all along
the rockstar was just a crappy lesser
god and then most of them killed
themselves so it's just
no i'm glad that's over it was a very
healthy thing at all
and iconology is is what people create
whether it's there or not
so it must be respected as a folk
religion and with all the force that
goes with it
and the mystery religion i was trying to
think about this because you when you
were talking about you were talking
about
um you know as if it was a a lesser
thing but it is lesser in one sense it's
lesser but it's also powerful it's it's
no no no no no no it's not
not it's not just no shit no no no
no it says lesser lesser means it's
closer to you because you're human
a lesser god is a god who's closer to
you as humans you like it might be not
real in an ultimate sense but it's real
in the sense
it's somebody you can mimic it's
somebody it's sutra it's somebody you
can mimic
you can't mimic an abstract almighty
universal god you cannot
mimic spinosus god the problem with
spinoza is
is modernism is completely monotheistic
with no
room for an iconology that's why
spin-off system was never religion
that's why i'm also saying that
synthesis as we wrote it will not be
practiced as a religion
because you're basically building the
hegelian version of the spinosist
religion
but that's where we have to start to do
metaphysics and philosophy properly
to create the religion of the elite you
write in the system book this is
not a handbook for a world religion no
this is philosophy this is metaphysics
and that's espinoza that's what's
feminism never became a religion at all
you can't have a church or spinal cell
because the only gods people can relate
to gods they can mimic the vast majority
people just want to god they can relate
to
like an old grandmother who died or
possibly
uh somebody for somebody ahead of you
who's not here yet
he's so old somebody from the future
somebody from the past you worship
and it's a lesser god that's what's
called lesser god lester god it's a
beautiful term for somebody you can
relate to
the higher gods you cannot relate to
that that's the problem with
monotheistic religion is that
catholicism at least through the saints
in there and i don't know
all the catholics go worship the saints
they have their own saint of their own
archetype or the city where they live
who they go worship
talk to and then the saint must talk to
god
in that order
have a lot of um right so well the
deities right is is you you
you uh in generation phase you generate
the deity like you generate
images of the deity it's sort of like um
it's like why people watch movies right
you you get totally immersed in this
um world it's not ultimately true you it
doesn't matter if it's ultimately true
it's archetypes but it's but you get you
you immerse yourself
in it and it's as true as it can be for
you in that
moment and then eventually you get you
go through stages right you go
the different stages of of of uh
religion at the highest stage the whole
house of cards collapsed right right
it's like
zen when they say that um you know you
know you kill the buddha or whatever
that's like
the final stage but but in the b but
then there's all these what they call in
buddhism skillful means
you know there's all kinds of skillful
means all kinds of
kind of you know experimental um
projects that you you know you work
through
for various reasons and and that leads
to various
you know results and because religious
about your personal journey through life
that's what religion ultimately is it's
not about god
the ultimate god is always spinoza's
universe or
the zhurvan of the servanites or
astranism or the brahman so it's
it's it's the breath of the universe and
time passing is processed that's
there's nothing beneath that but that's
a god that doesn't care about us
but that's god so that kind of abstract
god
is abstract concept yeah sure and hegel
says it's just an abstract concept it
cannot be understood any other way by
humanity but if you want a god
that's god that's why atheism is just
the silliest idea ever why not believe
in something you don't even understand
why spend time not believing something
you haven't even taken the time to
understand that's essentially what the
atheism is
so the question is just for your place
god and what kind of god on what level
is important to you and
as soon as you have a master you follow
in any way that's a god
sure sure yeah the parent is the lesser
god to the child
so the parent can then go off and pray
to sink in the church so the parent can
have a lesser god to follow
and the lesser god has a protective
saint of why
because the protective saints is the
ultimate archetype of the archetype you
belong to
with where you for example your
profession and your the kind of man or
the kind of woman you are where that
belongs so
you go into your mode of being you have
somebody you can follow mimic and we
want to mimic and if we can
make all the way to where we want to get
that's fine the only problem is that
there's a there's a point where
mimicking no longer pays off and that's
in moving to the realm of novelty
and neuron on innovation the the realm
of the
the completely new the event yeah
and that's what eventuality is
interested in novelty and novelty cannot
happen through mimicking
it can happen if you mimic and make a
mistake and suddenly realize you made it
differently than what you try to mimic
so it doesn't have to be on purpose it
doesn't have to be you have to be
conscious
but the fact that you do something in a
way that nobody's ever done it before
you come up with a word that nobody ever
thought of
you had an idea nobody ever thought
before that's novelty the only way to do
it is to stop mimicking and start
thinking freely
and that's a crazy wisdom and it means
maybe it means a bit of heresy here and
you know you have to kind of yeah yeah
yeah we were talking about heresy
earlier
you know smashing icons or well the
crazy wisdom teachers
obviously destroys the opportunity to
mimic so that's the ultimate format of
mimicking as we talked about before
that's why the crazy western
teaching is wonderful and it's behind
the bar absolute necessary that's what's
a shocking
and challenging place to be in but
you're right the heretic
or the antagonist you're looking for
challenge you to think differently
so at least for yourself you become new
because the heretic is not somebody
you copy or mimic then it's a tyrant no
the heretic somebody you listen to and
you react to it's like i don't know
about this
but okay i'm going to challenge my own
status quo so i'm going to challenge my
state by listening to you
and see if you might challenge me or
maybe we're both wrong but i can only
expose the rebel throne by listening to
you
which is another which is a dialectical
term the third alternative could be
right
i can only see it by being challenged by
somebody who's a heretic
all of that is part of antagonism which
i think is the word we should use now
for
creative fruitful expansive debate
and argumentation and that's
these places of integrity are the
monasteries we're looking for to replace
academia
yeah it has the word agony in it too
is it which is because it is it's an
agonizing process
it's an ant agony it's antioch
right yeah antagonic
thank you for an antagonic conversation
brother yeah awesome yeah well
thomas do you have any last uh
reflections or
things things to say because you're um
yeah we touched upon a lot of ideas
again that's like
more than two hours i might have to
divide this this one at you
i think that there's there's also a team
of integration right there's all these
thinkers that that have not really been
brought into contact with each other you
know we haven't for example there is
nietzsche there's gerard
there's whitehead and so so i think
there's a lot of work ahead to
to take the most valuable ideas and kind
of
apply them in the right way um because
nietzsche so
i think that gerard's critique of nature
for example is very spot-on
i think he really i think there are some
some definitely some blind spots in in
in nietzsche that that girard uh exposed
but on the other hand
nietzsche understands something that
girard doesn't understand because
because nietzsche can work with the
dionysian which
which girard purely sees as a problem
which it isn't because that's what you
what you basically learn in tantra right
you
this dionysian is actually also very
very valuable so i think that
this these conversations are very
interesting because because they're
basically also just
engaging with a lot of different
thinkers that have not been been put
into contact with each other
or at least not to not to the to the
extent that uh
that that we need them i agree
completely
that's why i i call myself hey gail in
the sense that i built from hegel
because he was the last major thinker of
systems and i would have a system at the
end of the day
so but all these guys we talk about are
the sons of hegel
to me and i i think what i'm adamant
about is that the break between content
hegel is the real revolution we're still
dealing with we've only begun to
understand that revolution
and and that's on a par i think we're
going to argue in the book that
sorastar's invention of eventology
and the shift between content hegel are
to me philosophically speaking
the two most dramatic things that have
happened in the history of thinking as i
know it
and maybe we caught up with the ontology
and finally began to understood it fully
with a shift from con to hegel
but it's um that's where i'm at say the
shift from christianity to
post-christianity not
back to christianity but to
post-christianity it's also again kant
to hegel well you know it will be
interesting where christianity goes from
because
christianity has been evolving for it
for 2000 years right i mean there is no
such thing as christianity i mean
if christianity wants to survive and i
think it uh it wants that
then it will have to deal with the
modern society and
and and become relevant or become
relevant again
yeah and that and i would then suggest
she become relevant by being ahead of
the time instead of trying to catch up
yeah i i totally agree since 1960 mark
stallman is right about this but it's
1961 where they
threw a latin out and took in local
language it's just been imitating bad
protestantism and again
it's protestantism that has celebrity
worship catholicism has kept the saints
that's acceptable catholic cultures do
not have the celebrity problem
the way we have it in american europe
that's why they will have to have the
same lynch mobs that we do
catholicism is to certain extent immune
to that simply because they have already
structured in place that's very stable
over time and they can always return to
it
i think the catholic church is also an
amazing institution when it comes to
power and scope
that should not be underplayed here
because when you go into periods of
chaos
big institutions that are stuck and have
resources
and can weather things survive and
protestantism has none of those places
because it lacks a center
and because it's completely
decentralized and essentially a bunch of
cults with
sort of strong leaders that are no
longer strong or even respected i think
protestantism
will go away before catholicism goes
well a lot of people are moving back to
the orthodox
that's true yeah which i find
interesting because i find the orthodox
to be more into symbolism which is
closer to uh vagina
yeah it's closer to judaism for sure
yeah and closer to sarasota's too it is
historically so
yeah i'm not surprised that people are
going into deep history
men are going to the root of the phallus
which means
where is my line is where do i come from
and go deeper and deeper and deeper into
that that's exactly why the only thing
i've got with girard is to go even
deeper than gerard did
that means going into egypt and persia a
division he doesn't discuss
he starts with christianity and that
daddy does fine
no no no no no no no no
absolute beginning so he has a theory of
language
that is also um that also depends on
builds on the victimization mechanism so
she write um definitely looks at at the
absolute beginning yeah but he jumps
from there straight on to christianity
and even freud
does not discuss persian the persian
heritage so when freud sits in moses and
monotheism it talks about monopolism
it's like yeah moses was the leader of
egyptian cult but it's not like the
egyptians invented monotheism
they mimicked it and did a bad version
of it the original version was persian
and we all know that by now
but freud didn't in 1938. so even now
only like 50 years later we know much
more than these guys did
and the problem with gerard is that he
he
but he then later discusses with the
development
prior to that so there's like a big jump
in gerard that's lacking that's what
it is
it did write a book about uh brahmanism
so that's on my to read list
um great let's look into that together
that could be really interesting yeah
that could fill the gap maybe it was
there
early on like people read freud and
they don't read taught them in taboo and
they don't read moses and manifest and
without those two books you don't see
the full freud
it's impossible let's dig into that all
right and the damn martyrs
they're problematic what do we do with
them
so martyrs and what's next
what's next alexander before we leave
anybody who watches and listens to this
you're welcome to try to contact us and
you know the questions we're asking here
uh please answer them for us if you have
the answer
uh or going to antagonia and
going to debate with us we all become
richer and smarter in the process
richer yeah i hope so but
no mobs no mobs no bugs
no please don't just don't it's too
vulgar
too boring all right guys
okay thanks so much for watching thank
you